Mayank C Koli | Sr. DevOps Engineer/Cloud Engineer

- New Delhi, India
- +91-882-663-4734
- mayank.c.koli@gmail.com
- Skype mayankkoli | | github.com/manukoli1986 | in linkedin.com/in/mayankckoli Date of birth Dec 1st 1988 | Nationality Indian | Marital Status Single



Summary

10+ years of hands of experience in Software industry, having wide experience in managing from Datacentre operations to multi Cloud platforms. Skilled in Python, Agile methodologies, with Best Practices of DevOps / Site Reliability Engineering, High Availability, Orchestration, CI/CD Jenkins pipelines, DR, Monitoring, Centralize Logging, Configuration Management, and Development.

Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect, CKA, CKAD, Terraform Associate, RHCE, RHCVA, Jenkins Training, MCSA

Project Summary

- Designed Multiple Automation solutions on Cloud using tools i.e. python, boto3, lambda, cloud event, SNS, could watch
- Created Step functions for AWS Resource which will run in lambda like Jenkins pipeline to run stages
- Designed program to detect stable & moving images using OpenCV modules using cascading templates
- Design and implement CICD pipelines to automate the Application lifecycle @ Bharti Airtel
- Migrated On-Prem VMs to AWS Cloud using terraform @ Amex

Professional Experience

Cognizant Softvision, Noida, India.

Senior Associate – Projects

Apr 2021 – Present

- Proficient with Kubernetes and ability to design and implement end-to-end container management solution with Kubernetes
- Experienced in the architecture and engineering of secure and reliable hybrid cloud-oriented solutions between (AWS & On-Prem) leveraging the DevSecOps paradigm (i.e. Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, etc.)
- Design and implement complex AWS projects aligned with Cloud best practices to ensure robust solutions in a cross-functional technology Team
- Work closely with development teams to diagnose performance, reliability and security issues in applications and system design
- Using Helm Chart Museum for Production Deployments on EKS.
- Expertise in container architecture, Docker universal packaging and store them in private Docker Registry, container orchestration and Micro services architecture pattern
- Design automation solution on cloud using AWS Lambda Function
- Managing Services in overall AWS infrastructure (EC2, S3, VPC, RDS, ECS) and containerizing existing applications
- Knowledge of messaging Queues like Kafka and managing LB via Nginx for App traffic
- Design HA CI/CD Platform with Jenkins and Ansible
- Managing middle ware applications like Weblogic and storing artifacts to Nexus
- Using GIT to centralize code and publish them with across team
- Working within small highly collaborative Agile teams with their short release cycles

HCL Technology Pvt Ltd, Noida, India.

Kev Skills

Cloud Platforms: Open stack, Hybrid Cloud, AWS,

GCP and Azure

IAAC: Packer, Terraform

Containerization: Dockers & Kubernete, EKS, GKE,

AKS

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Nosql

Automation & DevOps Tools: Terraform, Puppet/Ansible, GIT, Bitbucket, Jenkins, KVM, Python, Bash, Web Servers (Apache, Nginx), Jmeter, Helm Chart Museum, aws-cli/boto3

Monitoring: Splunk, Nagios, ELK, Prometheus &

Grafana

Network: AWS CloudFront, Akamai

Programing Skills: Python, Bash, HTML, CSS

Senior DevOps Engineer

Jul 2018 – Apr 2021

Developed tools to facilitate production system uptime and achieving product SLA. Automated production deployment using Jenkins Pipeline with infrastructure Automation and Orchestration. Automated all daily Adhoc manual process. Troubleshoot operational and application issues and fix them within the SLA.

Atem Corp Pvt Ltd, Chennai, India.

DevOps Engineer

Feb 2017 - May 2018

Developed tools to facilitate production system uptime and achieving product SLA. Automated production deployment using Jenkins Pipeline with infrastructure Automation and Orchestration. Automated all daily Ad-hoc manual process. Troubleshoot operational and application issues and fix them within the SLA.

Aspen Communication Pvt. Ltd., Noida, India

Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

System Admin

Linux Administrator supported all the OS and application level issues for assigned services. Monitored the Websites which managed by magneto, built on LAMP and REDIS for caching purpose. Deployed servers and managed cloud platform: AWS (Amazon Web Services). Configure Firewall Cyberoam for the organization. Website data backup and restoration process. Handling assignment of task in JIRA as well as GIT as online repository.

CHI Networks Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, India

Jan 2015 - Aug 2016

Linux System Engineer

Deployed, managed and maintained hosting (Domain, webmail, Web) more than 200+ client across country. Responsible for complete handling all the OS and application level issues for assigned services as well as worked on call 24*7 pager rotations and first level escalation operations. Designed and developed infrastructure monitoring and reporting tools for Linux, network and security systems. Managed LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL and PHP) applications like Word Press, Drupal, Joomla and Moodle with provide OPENVPN connectivity (site-to-site + user VPN)

Progression Infonet Pvt. Ltd., Gurugram, India

Sept 2014 - Jan 2015

System Administrator

L2/L3 Support ownership of all Managed Services hosting of products (cpanel, plesk, cloud, dedicated). System administration of complete server farm of Linux/Windows Servers, Database management, Network Monitoring (OpenNMS, Nagios), Centralised logging.

INS E Solution Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, India

Mar 2011 - Sept 2014

Linux System Administrator

Installation, configuration and management of Linux Servers. Configuring TCP/IP Networking services as per the Client requirements. It Includes Configuring File & Print Servers, Mail servers (Send mail), DNS and DHCP both in Linux. Setup PXE boot environment. Upgraded and configured Linux servers and installed network routers, cabling, and firewall. Handled network including Cisco Routers, L2-L3 Switches and Firewall. Installation, configuration and managed several applications running on Linux servers like Spark, XAMPP, HRM applications User & group Management with Advance Permission Like ACL, Disk Quota, Squid, SGID, Sticky bit. Provided systems administration in office using Linux/ Windows Servers operating systems.

Education

- Bachelors in Commerce from School Of Open Learning University, Delhi, India (May 2007 May 2011)
- Diploma in Computer Hardware and Networking from ICA Shine Pvt Ltd, Delhi, India (Mar 2008 Jun 2009)

Personal Profile

Marital Status Single

Language Proficiency Hindi, English (Excellent in Reading, Writing and Verbal)

Passport Number K3331233

I get stuff done. You can trust me to deliver the task on time and I really enjoy the responsibility given to me which teaches me always something NEW.